Finding Aid for the Dewey Daane Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Special Report of the National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Policies- Letter transmitting a Special Report on the Proposed Replenishment of the Resources of the International Development Association (Box 51)
- National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Policies- Annual Report to the President and to the Congress, July 1, 1968- June 30, 1969 (Box 51)
- National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Problems- Special Report to the President and to the Congress on the Proposed International Development Association-, February 1960 (Box 51)
- National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Problems- Ninth Special Report to the President and to the Congress-, April 1962- June 1964 (Box 51)
- National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Problems-Communication from the President of the United States and Special Report of the Council Relative to Proposed Increases in Quotas of the International Monetary Fund-, March 1965 (Box 51)
- National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Policies- Special Report to the President and to the Congress on the Proposed U.S. Contribution to the Consolidated Special Funds of the Asian Development Bank-, January 1970 (Box 51)
- National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Policies- Special Report to the President and to the Congress on U.S. Participation in a Proposed Replenishment of the Resources of the Inter-American Development Bank-, May 1970 (Box 51)
- Princeton Studies in International Finance, No. 10- Reserve-Asset Preferences of Central Banks and Stability of the Gold-Exchange Standard- Peter B. Kenen- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University, 1963 (Box 51)
- Princeton Studies in International Finance, No. 12- The Evolution of the International Monetary System: Historical Reappraisal and Future Perspectives- Robert Triffin- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University, 1964 (Box 51)
- Princeton Studies in International Finance, No. 13- The Management of the Dollar in International Finance- Robert Z. Aliber- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University, 1964 (Box 51)
- Princeton Studies in International Finance, No. 20-An Empirical Study of the Foreign-Exchange Market: Test of a Theory- Fred R. Glahe- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University, 1967 (Box 51)
- Princeton Studies in International Finance, No. 33- The Reconstruction of the International Monetary System: The Attempts of 1922 and 1933- Stephen V. O. Clarke- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University, 1973 (Box 51)
- Special Papers in International Economics No. 3, Revised March 1964- Plans for Reform of the International Monetary System- Fritz Machlup- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Reprints in International Finance No. 1, August 1965- The Cloakroom Rule of International Reserves: Reserve Creation and Resources Transfer- Fritz Machlup- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Reprints in International Finance No. 2, September 1965- Real Adjustment, Compensatory Corrections, and Foreign Financing of Imbalances in International Payments- Fritz Machlup- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Reprints in International Finance No. 3, February 1966- International Monetary Systems and the Free market Economy- Fritz Machlup- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Reprints in International Finance No. 4, September 1966- World Monetary Debate- Bases For Agreement- Fritz Machlup- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Reprints in International Finance No. 5, October 1966- The Need for Monetary Reserves-Fritz Machlup- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Reprints in International Finance No. 7, September 1967- Credit Facilities or Reserve Allotments?- Fritz Machlup- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Reprints in International Finance No. 8, October 1967- From Dormant Liabilities to Dormant Assets- Fritz Machlup- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Reprints in International Finance No. 9, February 1968- Reparations in the Postwar Period: A Survey- Benjamin J. Cohen- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Reprints in International Finance No. 10, September 1968- The Price of Gold- Fritz Machlup- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Reprints in International Finance No. 11, October 1968- The Transfer Gap of the United States- Fritz Machlup- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Reprints in International Finance No. 18, June 1975- Floats, Glides and Indicators: A Comparison of Methods for Changing Exchange Rates- Peter B. Kenen- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Reprints in International Finance No. 22, September 1982- Exchange Rate Behavior with Currency Inconvertibility- Jorge Braga De Macedo- International Finance Section, Dept. of Economic, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 46, May 1965- Balance-of-Payments Deficits and the International Market for Liquidity- Charles P. Kindleberer- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 49, November 1965- Requirements of and International Reserve System- Tibor Scitovsky- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 50, December 1965- The Crawling Peg- John H. Williamson- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 53, April 1966- Problems of the International Monetary System- Milton Gilbert- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 54, May 1966- Reserves, Reserve Currencies, and Vehicle Currencies: An Argument- Robert V. Roosa and Fred Hirsch- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 55, September 1966- The Balance of Payments and the Foreign Investment Position of the United States- Robert Triffin- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 56, October 1966- United States Gold Policy: The Case for Change- John Parke Young- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 57, January 1967- A Dollar-Reserve System as a Transitional Solution- Gunther Ruff- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 58, February 1967- Toward Assessing the Need for International Reserves- J. Marcus Fleming- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 59, April 1967- New Proposals for the International Finance of Development- N. T. Wang- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 60, June 1967- Gold: Barbarous Relic or Useful Instrument?- Miroslav A. Kriz- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 61, August 1967- The Politics of International Money and World Language- Charles P. Kindleberger- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 62, October 1967- Optimum Adjustment Processes and Currency Areas- Delbert A. Snider- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 63, November 1967- Changing the United States Commitment to Gold- Eugene A. Birnbaum- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 64, February 1968- The Euro-Dollar Market: An Interpretation- Alexander K. Swoboda- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 65, March 1968- The Euro-Dollar market: Some Unsolved Issues- Fred H. Klopstock- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 66, April 1968- Gold and the International Monetary System: An Orderly Reform- Eugene A. Birnbaum- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 67, May 1968- Guidelines for Balance-of-Payments Adjustment Under the Par-Value System- J. Marcus Fleming- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 68, June 1968- International Financial Intermediation: Deficits Benign and Malignant- George N. Halm- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 69, July 1968- Foreign Aid-A Critique and a Proposal- Albert O/ Hirschman and Richard M. Bird- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 70, October 1968- The Gold-Dollar System: Conditions of Equilibrium and the Price of Gold- Milton Gilbert- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 97, February 1973- Exchange-Rate Rigidity, Investment Distortions and the Failure of Bretton Woods- Robert M. Dunn, Jr.- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 98, April 1973- The Case for European Monetary Integration- James G. Ingram- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 99, June 1973- An SDR Standard: Impetus, Elements, and Impediments- Fred Hirsch- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 100, September 1973- The Link Between Special Drawing Right and Development Finance- Y. S. Park- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 101, November 1973- National Preferences and the Scope for International Monetary Reform- Robert Z. Aliber- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 102, November 1973- Payments Arrangements for Less Developed Countries: The Role of Foreign Assistance- Constantine Michalopoulos- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 103, February 1974- Capital Flows and Exchange-Rate Flexibility and the Post-Bretton Woods Era- John H. Makin- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 104, May 1974- The Anatomy of Official Exchange-Rate Intervention Systems- Helmut W. Mayer- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 105, June 1974- Myths and Reality in the Development of International Affiars- F. Boyer De La Giroday- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 106, October 1974- A New Tripartite Monetary Agreement or a Limping Dollar Standard?- Ronald I. McKinnon- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 107, December 1974- Reflections on the International Monetary Reform- J. Marcus Fleming- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University [2 copies] (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 108, April 1975- Less Developed Countries and the Post- 1971 International Financial System- Carlos F. Diaz-Alejandro- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 109, April 1975- Rules for a Floating-Rate Regime- Raymond F. Mikesell and Henry N. Goldstein- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 110, June 1975- Financing Needs of Developing Countries: Proposals for International Action- Constantine Michalopoulos- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 111, June 1975- Are the Oil-Payments Deficits Manageable?- Gerald A. Pollack- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 113, December 1975- The Oil-Transfer Problem and International Economic Stability- Thomas D. Willett- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 114, April 1976- Artificial Currency Units: The Formation of Functional Currency Areas- Joseph Aschheim and Y. S. Park- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 115, April 1976- Reflections on Jamaica- Edward M. Bernstein et al.- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 117, June 1976- Domestic Origins of the Monetary Approach to the Balance of Payments- Herbert G. Grubel- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 119, December 1976- Exchange Policies for Less Developed Countries in a World of Floating Rates- Stanley W. Black- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 120, March 1977- Jamaica and the Par-Value System- George N. Halm- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 123, August 1977- The Presentation of the U.S. Balance of Payments: A Symposium- Robert M. Stern, Charles F. Schwartz, Robert Triffin, Edward M. Bernstein and Walther Lederer- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 125, December 1977- The Eurocurrency Market-Ronald I. McKinnon- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 126, December 1977- Leaning Against the Wind: A Standard for Managed Floating- Paula A. Tosini- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 130, December 1978- The Management of an Open Economy With “100% Plus” Wage Indexation- Franco Modigliani and Tommaso Padoa-Schioppa- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 131, December 1978- Reserve- Currency Preferences of Central Banks- H. Robert Heller and Malcolm Knight- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 132, December 1978- Gold and the Dollar Crisis: Yesterday and Tomorrow- Robert Triffin- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 142, June 1981- The European Monetary System: An Outsider’s View- Benjamin J. Cohen- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 143, July 1981- International Trade and Investment: Two Perspectives- Marina v. N. Whitman- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- Essays in International Finance No. 147, May 1982- International Financial Intermediation: A Long and Tropical View- Edmar Lisboa Bacha and Carlos F. Diaz Alejandro- International Finance Section, Dept of Economics, Princeton University (Box 51)
- The Arthur K. Salomon Lecture- The Role of Money in a Dynamic Economy- Per Jacobsson- Graduate School of Business Administration, New York University-, 1963 (Box 51)
- The Arthur K. Salomon Lecture- Money Will Not Manage Itself- Allan Sproul- Graduate School of Business Administration, New York University-, 1963 (Box 51)
- The Arthur K. Salomon Lecture- Economic Policy Since 1945: The Nature of Success-John Kenneth Galbraith- Graduate School of Business Administration, New York University (Box 51)
- The Arthur K. Salomon Lecture- International Capital Markets- The Right Honorable, The Earl of Cromer, M. B. E. - Graduate School of Business Administration, New York University (Box 51)
- The Per Jacobsson Foundation Lectures- Economic Growth and Monetary Stability- Maurice Frere and Rodrigo Gomez- November 9, 1964 [2 copies] (Box 51)
- Brooking Institution Reprint- Empirical Evidence on the Incidence of the Corporation Income Tax- John G. Cragg, rnold C. Harberger, and Peter Mieszkowski- Studies in Government Finance-, 1968 (Box 51)
- Brookings Research Report 81- Evaluating Economic Policies with the Brookings Model- Gary Fromm and Paul Taubman (Box 51)
- Brookings Research Report 83- The British Economy: Performance and Prospects-Richard E. Caves and Associates (Box 51)
- Contingency Planning- re the Dollar November 1970-April 1971 Rome G-10 Meeting, December 1971 (Box 67)
- May 5, 1971- Contingency Planning Meeting (Volcker’s Office) Federal Intervention:, April-May 1971 (Box 67)
- Dealing with the Overhang of Eurodollar Liabilities (Box 67)
- Dealing with the Overhang of Eurodollar—Ex-Im Borrowing (Box 67)
- Dealing with the Overhang of Eurodollar—MPS Borrowing (Box 67)
- - 1:00pm- Material for Luncheon with Gov. Carli, June 30, 1971 (Box 67)
- Sterling Operations (Box 67)
- U.K. Purchases- IMF (Box 67)
- Monetary Aggregates (Box 67)
- Leutwiler Correspondence (Box 67)
- Insurance Coverage for Government Securities (Box 67)
- Discussions with President Hayes New York Federal Reserve January 22, 1971 Capitol Controls (Box 67)
- EEC Margins (Box 67)
- Operations in Foreign Currencies During, 1969 (Box 67)
- Operations in Foreign Currencies During, 1972 (Box 67)
- Loose Materials (Box 67)
- Loose Materials bundled with Rubberbands- labeled Advance Refunding International Monetary Conference, June 5-8, 1973 (Misc.) Paris 1972 International Monetary Conference Montreal, Canada (Box 67)
- Montreal- Miscellaneous 1971 International Banking Conference Munich, Germany (Box 67)
  - International Banking Conference May 25-28, 1971 Munich, Germany Munich Speech 1971 Munich Meeting Notes (Box 67)
  - Munich- Miscellaneous (Box 67)
  - Munich Speech Reference Material (Box 67)
- Various Speeches-, 1973 (Box 68)
- Various Speeches-, 1972 (Box 68)
- Various Speeches-, 1971 (Box 68)
- Various Speeches- 1970 1970 Monetary Conference- ABA May 17-20, 1970 Hot Springs, Virginia (Box 68)
- ABA Monetary Conference Copenhagen, Denmark June 15-22, 1969 (Box 68)
- ABA Monetary Conference Dorado Beach, Puerto Rico May 19-24, 1968 (Box 68)
- ABA Monetary Conference Pebble Beach, California March 15-17, 1967 (Box 68)
- Speech Folder ABA Annual Convention October 22-27, 1966 San Francisco, California ABA Monetary Conference Madrid, Spain May 21-30 (Box 68)
- ABA Monetary Conference March 17, 1965 Princeton Inn Princeton, New Jersey (Box 68)
- ABA Monetary Conference Vienna, Austria May 19-22, 1964 (Box 68)
- Loose Materials (Box 68)
- Foreign Direct Investment Program (Box 68)
- Loose Pamphlets on U.S. Balance of Payments (Box 68)
- The Balance of Payments Problem-Answers to Questions to Gov. J.L. Robertson, May,17 (Box 68)
- 1965 (Box 68)
- Guidelines- Commerce Department (Box 68)
- Guidelines for Banks- Final (Box 68)
- Guidelines for Non-Banks- Final (Box 68)
- Review Committee for Balance of Payments Statistics (Box 68)
- Balance of Payments Statistical Review Committee (Box 68)
- Loose Materials (Box 68)
- Presentation of Balance of Payments Statistics (Box 68)
- Loose Materials on Balance of Payments - some bundled with rubberbands (Box 68)
- Blough Committee of Balance of Payments (Box 69)
- Review Committee on Balance of Payments Statistics Materials re Brookings Study on U.S. Balance of Payments (Box 69)
  - Loose Materials (Box 69)
  - U.S. Balance of Payments in 1968 Printed Pamphlets (Box 69)
- Sproul Report- Balance of Payments (Box 69)
- Meeting with the President September 11, 1963 Balance of Payments Memoranda to the President re Balance of Payments (Box 69)
- Meeting with the President November 19, 1962 Balance of Payments Meeting with the President April 18, 1963 Balance of Payments (Box 69)
- Loose Materials on Balance of Payments - some bundled with rubberbands (Box 69)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 1, 9/10/86 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Course #424 Fall, 1986 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 2, 9/24/86 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 3, 10/22/86 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 4, 10/29/86 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 5, 11/5/86 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 6, 11/12/86 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 7, 11/19/86 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 9, 12/3/86 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 8, 12/3/86 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Mid-term exam, 10/15/86 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Final exam, 12/18/86 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – course #424 Fall, 1985 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 1, 9/4/85 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Maneschi 9/11/85 and, 9/18/85 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Maneschi 10/2/85 and, 10/9/85 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 2, 9/25/85 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 2a 9/25/85 Balance of Payments (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 2b 9/25/85 LDC Debt Problem and Dollar Problem (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Midterm Exam, 10/16/85 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 3, 10/23/85 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 4, 10/30/85 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 5, 11/6/85 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics –11/7/85 Intl. Debt Problem-Azizali F. Mohammed (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 6, 11/13/85 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 7, 11/20/85 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 8, 12/4/85 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Final exam, 12/17/85 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Course #424 Fall, 1984 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Maneschi 9/12/84 and, 10/3/84 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Mid Semester exam, 10/10/84 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 1, 9/5/84 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 2, 10/17/84 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 3, 10/24/84 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 4, 10/31/84 (Box 70)
- International Finance and Economics – Lecture # 5, 11/7/84 (Box 70)